. >> GOOD AFTERNOON EVERYONE.
WELCOME TO THE SEPTEMBER 16TH, 2025 REGULAR MEETING OF THE SAN
FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS .
>> MADAM CLERK, WILL YOU PLEASE CALL THE ROLL?
YES. SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN PRESIDENT
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN PRESENT SUPERVISOR DORSEY DORSEY NOT
PRESENT SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO PRESENT SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER PRESENT SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD
PRESENT SUPERVISOR GENTLEMAN PRESENT MANDOLIN PRESENT
SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR PRESENT SUPERVISOR SADR SADR
PRESENT SUPERVISOR CHERYL SHERRELL PRESENT SUPERVISOR
WALTON WALTON PRESENT MR. PRESIDENT, DO YOU HAVE A
QUORUM? >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
>> COLLEAGUES SUPERVISOR DORSEY HAS JURY DUTY TODAY AND HAS
REQUESTED TO BE EXCUSED. CAN I HAVE A MOTION TO EXCUSE
HIM? MOVE BY SADR SECONDED BY CHERYL
. >> MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL THE ROLL ON THAT MOTION? >> YES.
SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN MY MANDOLIN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I
SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I
SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISE AROUND ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I VERY NICE WITHOUT OBJECTION SUPERVISOR
DORSEY IS EXCUSED FROM TODAY'S MEETING AND THE SAN FRANCISCO
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT WE ARE ON THE
UNCEDED ANCESTRAL HOMELAND OF THE ROMITA ALONI WHO ARE THE
ORIGINAL INHABITANTS OF THE SAN FRANCISCO PENINSULA AS THE
INDIGENOUS STEWARDS OF THIS LAND AND IN ACCORDANCE WITH
THEIR TRADITIONS THE ROMITA SALONI HAVE NEVER CEDED LOST
NOR FORGOTTEN THEIR RESPONSIBILITIES AS THE
CARETAKERS OF THIS PLACE AS WELL AS FOR ALL PEOPLES WHO
RESIDE IN THEIR TRADITIONAL TERRITORY.
WE AS GUESTS WE RECOGNIZE THAT WE BENEFIT FROM LIVING
AND WORKING ON THEIR TRADITIONAL HOMELAND.
WE WISH TO PAY OUR RESPECTS BY ACKNOWLEDGING THE ANCESTORS,
ELDERS AND RELATIVES OF THE RAMA SOCIAL ONLY COMMUNITY
AND BY AFFIRMING THEIR RIGHTS AS FIRST PEOPLES.
COLLEAGUES WILL YOU JOIN ME IN RECITING THE PLEDGE OF
ALLEGIANCE TO FIVE UNITED STATES TO THE REPUBLIC AS LONG
AS ON BEHALF OF THE BOARD I WANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE THE STAFF
AT S.F. GOVT'S TV AND TODAY THAT IS ESPECIALLY FOR KALEENA
MENDOZA. THEY RECORD EACH OF OUR
MEETINGS AND MAKE THE TRANSCRIPTS AVAILABLE TO THE
PUBLIC ONLINE. MADAM CLERK, DO YOU HAVE ANY
COMMUNICATIONS? >> YES, MR. PRESIDENT.
THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS WELCOMES YOU TO
ATTEND THIS MEETING AT CITY HALL IN THE BOARD'S LEGISLATIVE
CHAMBERS. SECOND FLOOR ROOM 250.
OR YOU MAY WATCH THE PROCEEDINGS ON S.F. GOV TV'S
CHANNEL 26 OR VIEW THE LIVESTREAM AT W W W DOT S.F.
GOV TV G. YOU MAY ALSO SUBMIT YOUR PUBLIC
COMMENT BY SENDING AN EMAIL TO B O S AT S.F. GOP BORG OR VIA
US POSTAL SERVICE TO THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
ONE DR. CARLTON B GOOD PLACE CITY HALL ROOM 244 SAN
FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA 9410 TWO TO MAKE A FUTURE REASONABLE
ACCOMMODATION REQUEST UNDER THE AMERICANS WITH DISABILITIES ACT
OR TO REQUEST LANGUAGE ASSISTANCE PLEASE CONTACT THE
CLERK'S OFFICE AT LEAST TWO BUSINESS DAYS IN ADVANCE BY
CALLING (415) 554-5184. MEMBERS MR. PRESIDENT, THAT
CONCLUDES THE COMMUNICATION. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
LET'S GO TO THE CONSENT AGENDA .
>> PLEASE CALL ITEMS ONE THROUGH TEN TOGETHER.
>> ITEMS ONE THROUGH TEN ARE ON CONSENT.
THESE ITEMS ARE CONSIDERED ROUTINE.
IF A MEMBER OBJECTS AN ITEM MAY BE REMOVED AND CONSIDERED
SEPARATELY. >> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON THE
CONSENT AGENDA ON ITEMS ONE THROUGH TEN SUPERVISOR MANDOLIN
I MENZEL MEAN I SUPERVISOR MELGAR I MELGAR I SUPERVISOR
SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I THERE ARE TEN
EYES WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY PASSED
AND THE RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO
UNFINISHED BUSINESS PLEASE CALL ITEMS 11 AND 12 ITEMS 11 AND 12
COMPRISE TWO SETTLEMENTS ITEM 11 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AUTHORIZE
A PARTIAL SETTLEMENT OF THE LAWSUIT FILED ON BEHALF OF THE
CITY AND THE PEOPLE OF THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA AGAINST
TRUST FOR THE BENEFIT OF MEMBERS OF THE RAYMOND SACKLER
FAMILY FOR ABATEMENT FUNDS IN THE RANGE OF 8 TO $12
MILLION TO BE PAID OVER 15 YEARS.
THE LAWSUIT INVOLVES ALLEGATIONS THAT PURDUE
AND SACKLERS CONTRIBUTED TO THE OPIOID CRISIS BY INCENTIVIZING
THE SALE AND USE OF OPIOIDS DESPITE KNOWLEDGE OF THE
GROWING EPIDEMIC CAUSED BY OPIOID MISUSE.
ITEM 12 IS AN ORDINANCE FILED BY THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO AGAINST AT&T CORP AND PACIFIC BELL TELEPHONE
COMPANY FOR APPROXIMATELY 15.4 MILLION.
>> THE LAWSUIT INVOLVES ALLEGATIONS THAT AT&T AND OTHER
TELECOMMUNICATION COMPANIES KNOWINGLY UNDER COLLECTED
AND UNDER REMITTED AMOUNTS DUE UNDER THE ACCESS LINE TAX
ORDINANCE IN VIOLATION OF THE CALIFORNIA FALSE CLAIMS ACT.
>> I THINK WE CAN TAKE 11 AND 12 SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION. THE ORDINANCES ARE FINALLY
PASSED. MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO NEW
BUSINESS. >> PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 13.
>> ITEM NUMBER 13 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE PLANNING
CODE TO WAIVE CERTAIN DEVELOPMENT IMPACT FEES IN THE
MARKET IN OCTAVIA AREA PLAN TO AMEND THE VAN AND VAN NESS
AND MARKET RESIDENTIAL SPECIAL USE DISTRICT TO PROVIDE THAT
THE MARKET IN OCTAVIA COMMUNITY ADVISORY COMMITTEE SHALL SUNSET
SIX MONTHS AFTER THE EFFECTIVE DATE OF THIS ORDINANCE AND TO
MAKE CONFORMING AMENDMENTS TO SOME OF THE DEFINITIONS IN THE
PLANNING CODE TO AFFIRM THE CYCLE DETERMINATION AND MAKE
THE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. SUPERVISOR CHAN THANK YOU
PRESIDENT AMENDMENT AND COLLEAGUES I THINK THIS ONE
IS A VERY TOUGH ONE. I ORIGINALLY THE FEE WAIVER IS
FOR THE ENTIRE AREA FOR ALL THE NOT ONLY FOR THE APPROVED
DEVELOPMENT NEEDS BUT ALSO THE FOR THE APPROVED DEVELOPMENTS
IN THE PIPELINE THAT HAS PERMIT OR FINAL APPROVAL
AND CONSTRUCTION POTENTIALLY GETTING A CONSTRUCTION PERMIT
BY JANUARY 2026 AS WELL AS THOSE THAT ACTUALLY HAVE YET TO
RECEIVE APPROVAL AT ALL PRIOR TO JANUARY 2026.
I THINK IN CONVERSATION OR WITH PRESENT AMENDMENT
AND SUPERVISOR DORSEY WHICH IS VICE CHAIR ON THE BUDGET
COMMITTEE WHO ACTUALLY MAKE THAT MOTION THAT I, I DO AGREE
THAT YOU KNOW WE SHOULD HAVE SET SOME LIMIT TO IT.
I PROPOSE A FIVE YEAR SUNSET DAY THERE'S THERE SEEMS TO BE
SOME CONVERSATION AROUND THAT BUT ULTIMATELY WE LAND IN A
SPACE WHERE WE ELIMINATE IT. THE THE PROJECT I HAVE YET TO
BE APPROVE AND LIMITED TO 26 PROJECT THERE HAS BEEN APPROVED
AND IN THE PIPELINE THAT THEY ARE ANTICIPATING GETTING
ALREADY GETTING THE FINAL APPROVAL OR THE CONSTRUCTION
PERMIT BY JANUARY 2026. >> I DO WANT TO CAUTION US
THOUGH AS WE CONTINUE TO POTENTIALLY SEE MORE OF THESE
IMPACT FEE WAIVERS WITH THAT AMENDMENT AT THE BUDGET
COMMITTEE. WHAT HAPPENED WAS THAT WE WERE
ANTICIPATING ABOUT $135 MILLION OF FEE WAIVER WITH THE
AMENDMENTS. >> NOW WE'RE EXPECTING A
ROUGHLY ABOUT $81 MILLION OF FEE WAIVER BUT THAT'S AT THE
EXPENSE OF AFFORDABLE HOUSING INFRASTRUCTURE AND AS WELL AS
COMMUNITY FACILITIES. THOSE ARE THE CRITICAL
COMMUNITY BENEFITS THAT OUGHT TO BE REALLY BENEFITING THAT
VERY SAME AREA. I KNOW THAT WITH THESE FEE
WAIVER ACCORDING TO INFORMATION PROVIDED BY THE OFFICE OF
ECONOMIC AND WORKFORCE DEVELOPMENT IS THAT WE WILL
THEN BOOST HOUSING DEVELOPMENTS OF COURSE INCLUDING SOME ARE
AFFORDABLE HOUSING DEVELOPMENT AND PRODUCTION WITH THESE FEE
WAIVER DUE TO THE CURRENT ECONOMY.
I CAN UNDERSTAND THAT ARGUMENT AND I CAN SEE THAT AS A PART
PART OF THE INVESTMENTS TO HAVE MORE HOUSING IN THAT VERY AREA
THAT WE WANT TO SEE MORE AND GIVEN IN IT'S A PROXIMITY
TO MID-MARKET BUT I THINK THAT I WILL NOT BE IN SUPPORTIVE OF
SEEING MORE OF THE IMPACT FEE WAIVERS SHOULD SHOULD WE
ACTUALLY GOING TO HAVE MORE IN THE COMING MONTHS.
SO FOR THAT THANK YOU. >> THANK YOU CHAIR CHAN
SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANK YOU PRESIDENT BERMAN COLLEAGUES, I
AM GRATEFUL THAT THIS ITEM HAS BEEN AMENDED TO INCLUDE ONLY
THE CURRENT PIPELINE PROJECTS RATHER THAN ELIMINATE THE
IMPACT FEES ALTOGETHER. >> THIS MEASURE IS PERMANENTLY
RENEGING ON LAND'S LONG STANDING COMMITMENTS TO MARKET
AND OCTAVIA AREA PLAN COMMUNITIES WHILE THE MARKET
AND OCTAVIA AREA PLAN PREDOMINANTLY COVERS
NEIGHBORING DISTRICTS, THERE IS A SMALL PORTION THAT INCLUDES
DISTRICT NINE. IN FACT JUST TWO YEARS AGO THIS
BOARD UNANIMOUSLY DENIED AN APPEAL TO WAIVE COMMUNITY
IMPACT FEES FOR A DISTRICT NINE DEVELOPMENT WITHIN THE MARKET
IN OCTAVIA AREA PLAN. WITH THIS ORDINANCE WE WILL BE
FORFEITING $81 MILLION IN LOST REVENUE FOR COMMUNITIES THAT IS
LOSING OVER $47 MILLION OF REVENUE FOR COMMUNITY
INFRASTRUCTURE AND OVER 33 MILLION IN AFFORDABLE HOUSING
FEES. WE HAVE A HOUSING ELEMENT
MANDATE TO BUILD 46,000 AFFORDABLE HOMES YET WE ARE
UNDERMINING THAT VERY MANDATE BY WAIVING ESSENTIAL AFFORDABLE
HOUSING INVESTMENT. >> I UNDERSTAND THAT THE
PROPONENTS FOR THIS ORDINANCE ARGUE THAT THESE 26 PIPELINE
PROJECTS ARE DESPERATELY NEEDED AND THAT SOME OF THESE PROJECTS
HAVE BEEN STALLED FOR UP TO FIVE YEARS.
>> WHAT IS STILL NOT EVIDENT IS THAT WAIVING THESE IMPACT FEES
WILL ACTUALLY CREATE ANY NEW HOUSING.
>> OUR PLANNING DEPARTMENT ITSELF HAS ACKNOWLEDGED THAT
ECONOMIC CONDITIONS SUCH AS HIGH INTEREST RATES
AND CONSTRUCTION COSTS ARE RESPONSIBLE FOR HOUSING
CONSTRUCTION DELAYS NOT IMPACT FEES WHILE EVICTION RATES ARE
SKYROCKETING HIGHER THAN EVER IN SAN FRANCISCO WHILE RENTS
ARE RISING, WE ARE CONTINUING ON A DANGEROUS PATH TOWARDS
GIVEAWAYS FOR DEVELOPERS AND PRIVATE INTERESTS AT THE
EXPENSE OF HOUSING WORKING FAMILIES.
>> DEVELOPER GIVEAWAYS LIKE THIS FURTHER PROVE THAT SAN
FRANCISCO IS BECOMING A PLACE ONLY AFFORDABLE TO THE WEALTHY.
AND FOR THESE REASONS I WILL BE VOTING NO THANK YOU MADAM CLERK
PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM 13 SUPERVISOR MAN.
HI I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER SADR I
SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON NO WALTON NO
SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FIELDER NO SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I THERE ARE
EIGHT EYES AND TWO NOSE WITH SUPERVISORS WALTON AND FIELDER
VOTING NO THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM
CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM NUMBER 14.
>> ITEM NUMBER 14 IS AN ORDINANCE TO APPROPRIATE
400,000 FROM GENERAL CITY RESPONSIBILITY
AND APPROXIMATELY 14,000 FROM THE DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC WORKS
AND APPROPRIATE FOR DISTRICT SEVEN PROJECTS IN THE AMOUNT OF
APPROXIMATELY 164,000 TO DPW FOR MEDIAN IMPROVEMENTS
IN MONTERREY HEIGHTS NEW CURB RAMPS IN WESTWOOD PARK SIDEWALK
REPAIR AND INGLESIDE TERRACES AND FOR WESTWOOD PARK PILLARS
TO THE DEPARTMENT OF DCF FOR PLAYGROUND UPDATE AND BLACKTOP
AT WEST PEARL ELEMENTARY SCHOOL AND AM FOR A MURAL AND SIGNAGE
AND UPDATES AT COMMODORE SLOAT ELEMENTARY 50,000 TO THE ARTS
COMMISSION FOR A MURAL ON MONTEREY BOULEVARD AND 50,000
TO THE IWD FOR A SERIES OF ART POP UPS ON OCEAN AVENUE.
>> PLEASE CALL THE ROLL ON ITEM 14 SUPERVISOR AMENDMENT I
AMENDMENT I SUPERVISOR MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SAUTER
SAUTER I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL I SUPERVISOR WALTON
WALTON I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I
SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR
FIELDER FILTER I SUPERVISOR OF MAHMOOD MAHMOOD EITHER TEN EYES
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING
MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 15.
>> ITEM NUMBER 15 IS A RESOLUTION TO APPROVE
MODIFICATION NUMBER FIVE TO AIRPORT CONTRACT PROJECT
MANAGEMENT SUPPORT SERVICES FOR THE SAN FRANCISCO INTERNATIONAL
AIRPORT INTERNATIONAL TERMINAL BUILDING PHASE TWO PROJECT WITH
AGS INCORPORATED TO INCREASE THE CONTRACT AMOUNT BY 2.85
MILLION FOUR IN TOTAL NOT TO EXCEED AMOUNT OF 12.5 MILLION
AND EXTEND THE CONTRACT TERM FOR SERVICES BY 187 DAYS FROM
JUNE 27TH 2026 FOR A TOTAL TERM OF JUNE 16TH 2020 THROUGH TO
DECEMBER 31ST 2026. >> WE CAN TAKE THIS SAME HOUSE
SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 16 ITEM NUMBER 16 IS A
RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE RECREATION AND PARKS DEPARTMENT
TO ACCEPT IN-KIND GRANT FROM THE UNION SQUARE ALLIANCE
VALUED AT APPROXIMATELY 300,000 FOR SOUND SYSTEM IMPROVEMENTS
AT THE UNION SQUARE PLAZA STAGE AND AGAIN SAME HOUSE, SAME
CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
17. >> ITEM NUMBER 17 AS A
RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE EXECUTION DELIVERY
AND PERFORMANCE OF THE FIRST AMENDMENT TO PORT LEASE TO THE
PORT LEASE FOR BUILDING 49 LOCATED AT 701 ILLINOIS STREET
WITHIN CRANE COVE PARK BETWEEN THE PORT OF SAN FRANCISCO
AND THE YOUNG MEN'S CHRISTIAN ASSOCIATION AND TO ELIMINATE
THE PROVISION WHICH WOULD REDUCE BY $6,000 THE AMOUNT OF
RENT CREDITS THAT ARE INTENDED TO OFFSET OPERATION
AND MAINTENANCE COSTS WITH THE PUBLIC RESTROOMS AND PROVIDE
150,000 AND NEW RENT CREDITS TO PARTIALLY OFFSET UNEXPECTED
COSTS RELATED TO IMPROVING THE STRUCTURAL CONDITION OF
BUILDING 49. >> SAME HOUSE SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
MADAME CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 18.
>> ITEM NUMBER 18 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE BUSINESS
TAX REGULATIONS CODE TO REDUCE THE TAX RATE ON GROSS RECEIPTS
FROM TELECOMMUNICATION BUSINESS ACTIVITIES BY MOVING THOSE
ACTIVITIES FROM CATEGORY FIVE TO CATEGORY FOUR FOR PURPOSES
OF THE GROSS RECEIPTS TAX AND THE HOMELESSNESS GROSS
RECEIPTS TAX AND TO RETAIN TAXPAYER'S ELIGIBILITY TO TAKE
THE TAX CREDIT FOR OPENING A PHYSICAL LOCATION IN DESIGNATED
AREAS OF THE CITY. THIS ITEM PURSUANT TO BUSINESS
AND TAX REGULATIONS CODE 2811 REQUIRES APPROVAL BY A
SUPERMAJORITY OR AT LEAST EIGHT MEMBERS OF THE WATER
SUPERVISORS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
>> WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST
READING. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
19. >> ITEM NUMBER 19 IS A
RESOLUTION TO AUTHORIZE THE MAYOR THE MAYOR'S CHIEF OF
STAFF. CHIEF OF PUBLIC SAFETY.
ASSISTANT CHIEF OF PUBLIC SAFETY POLICY ADVISOR AND THE
CHIEF OF THE FIRE DEPARTMENT TO SOLICIT DONATIONS FROM VARIOUS
PUBLIC PRIVATE ENTITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS TO SUPPORT
THE PROVISION OF CANCER SCREENING FOR ELIGIBLE FIRE
DEPARTMENT EMPLOYEES FOR SIX MONTHS FROM THE EFFECTIVE DATE
OF THIS RESOLUTION. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTIONS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 20.
>> ITEM NUMBER 20 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE
SUBDIVISION CODE TO STABLISH PROCEDURES REGARDING RESALE
PRICES, CAPITAL IMPROVEMENT COSTS, MARKETING AND SALES
POLICY FOR CONVEYANCE THROUGH INHERITANCE TITLE CHANGES
OWNING OCCUPYING AND REFINANCING BELOW MARKET
RATE CONDOMINIUM CONVERSION UNITS AND CLARIFYING EFFECTIVE
DATES FOR REQUIREMENTS APPLICABLE TO BMR UNITS
PURCHASED ON OR AFTER OCTOBER 1ST 2025.
>> SAME HOUSE SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE IS
PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL ITEM 20 ONE.
>> ITEM NUMBER 21 IS AN ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE BUILDING
CODE TO REMOVE LOCAL REQUIREMENTS REGARDING
COMMERCIAL LIGHTING, ROOFTOP MECHANICAL PENTHOUSES, DRIVEWAY
AND SIDEWALK LOAD LIMITS AND THE PROTECTION ACT TO
AFFIRM THE SECOND DETERMINATION AND MAKE APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
ORDINANCE IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK PLEASE CALL
ITEM 22. >> ITEM NUMBER 22 IS AN
ORDINANCE TO AMEND THE HEALTH CODE TO CLARIFY THE CITY'S
ENHANCED VENTILATION STANDARDS BY CODIFYING THE REQUIREMENT
THAT ALL NEW BUILDINGS AND MAJOR RENOVATIONS OF
BUILDINGS THAT CONTAIN A SENSITIVE USE CERTIFY THAT THE
BUILDING'S VENTILATION SYSTEM IS CAPABLE OF MAINTAINING
POSITIVE PRESSURE AND MAKING APPROPRIATE FINDINGS.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCE
IS PASSED ON FIRST READING MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
20 THREE. >> ITEM NUMBER 23 IS AN
ORDINANCE TO ORDER THE SUMMARY VACATION OF A PUBLIC SERVICES
MEANT FOR PUBLIC UTILITY PURPOSES AT 112 KENSINGTON WAY
AUTHORIZE THE CITY TO QUIT CLAIM ITS INTEREST IN THE
VACATION AREA TO KEVIN JENKINS AND LITTLE FOR $20,000 TO
AFFIRM THE SEQUEL DETERMINATION AND MAKE THE APPROPRIATE
FINDINGS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE ORDINANCES PASSED ON FIRST
READING MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 24.
>> ITEM 24 IS A RESOLUTION TO GRANT REVOKABLE PERMISSION TO
BRIDGE POTRERO COMMUNITY ASSOCIATES LLC TO MAINTAIN
ENCROACHMENTS IN THE PUBLIC RIGHT AWAY INCLUDING BUT NOT
LIMITED TO CUSTOMERS PAVING MATERIALS BENCHES, LANDSCAPING,
IRRIGATION, DRAINAGE FACILITIES, WALKWAYS
AND RETAINING WALLS. DELEGATED AUTHORITY TO THE
PUBLIC WORKS DIRECTOR TO ASSIGN RESPONSIBILITY AND ADOPT THE
APPROPRIATE FINDINGS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 25.
ITEM NUMBER 25 IS A RESOLUTION TO URGE A PREVENTATIVE
INTER-AGENCY AND DATA DRIVEN APPROACH TO ENDING SEVERE
AND FATAL TRAFFIC CRASHES BY DESIGNING AND ENFORCING SAFER
STREETS FOR ALL SAN FRANCISCANS WITH A PARTICULAR FOCUS ON
PROTECTING CHILDREN, SENIORS AND OTHER VULNERABLE
POPULATIONS. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL.
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED.
>> MADAME CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 20 SIX.
ITEM 26 IS A MOTION TO APPOINT AMANDA PYLE TO THE CHILDREN
FAMILY AND FAMILIES FIRST COMMISSION TERM AND IN OCTOBER
EIGHTH 2026. >> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL
WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION IS THAT THE MOTION IS APPROVED.
MADAME CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM 27.
>> ITEM 27 IS A MOTION TO APPROVE THE MAYOR'S NOMINATION
FOR THE APPOINTMENT OF JORDAN WILSON TO THE ENTERTAINMENT
COMMISSION FOR A TERM ENDING JULY 1ST, 2029.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION, THE MOTION
IS APPROVED. MADAM CLERK, PLEASE CALL ITEM
28. >> ITEM NUMBER 28 IS A MOTION
TO APPROVE THE MAYOR'S NOMINATION FOR THE
REAPPOINTMENT OF BIANCA NEWMAN TO THE BUILDING INSPECTION
COMMISSION. TERM ENDING JULY 1ST, 2027.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION
IS APPROVED. AND MADAM CLERK, LET'S GO TO
OUR COMMITTEE REPORTS. ITEM 29 WAS CONSIDERED BY THE
RULES COMMITTEE AT A REGULAR MEETING ON MONDAY, SEPTEMBER
15TH, 2025. IT IS A MOTION TO APPROVE
PRESIDENT RAFAEL MENDELSSOHN'S NOMINATION FOR THE
REAPPOINTMENT OF ELIZABETH ALEXANDER TUT TO THE BUILDING
INSPECTION COMMISSION TERM ENDING JULY 1ST, 2027.
>> SAME HOUSE, SAME CALL. >> WITHOUT OBJECTION THE MOTION
IS APPROVED AND LET'S GO TO ROLL CALL.
>> FIRST UP ON ROLL CALL TODAY IS MR. PRESIDENT.
>> ALL RIGHT. I HAVE TWO ITEMS TODAY,
COLLEAGUES WANTED TO LET YOU KNOW THAT I'LL BE HAVING MY
FIFTH HEARING ON TRAFFIC ENFORCEMENT IN SAN FRANCISCO ON
SEPTEMBER 25TH AT THE PUBLIC SAFETY AND NEIGHBORHOOD
SERVICES COMMITTEE. IF CHAIR DORSEY WERE HERE I
WOULD THANK HIM. I WANT TO THANK THE OTHER
MEMBERS OF THE COMMITTEE FOR FINDING TIME FOR US TO CONTINUE
OUR ONGOING DIALOG WITH S.F. PD AND S.F. MTA ON THE TOPIC AND I
WANT TO THANK SUPERVISOR SHERYL FOR SIGNING ON AS A CO-SPONSOR
. WE DO HAVE SOME GOOD NEWS AHEAD
OF THIS HEARING. THE STEEP AND AND STEADY
DECLINE IN TRAFFIC CITATIONS GOING BACK TO 2014 APPEARS TO
HAVE FINALLY STOPPED AND WE HAVE SEEN A MODEST BUT
SUSTAINED INCREASE IN SITE CITATIONS SINCE THE LATEST
REPORTS SHOW A 21 AND 21% INCREASE IN TRAFFIC CITATIONS
FOR THE FIRST HALF OF 2025 COMPARED TO THE FIRST HALF OF
2024 AND THAT'S AFTER A 59% INCREASE IN CITATIONS FOR 2024
OVER 2023. WE'RE ALSO BEGINNING TO SEE
MEASURABLE POSITIVE RESULTS FROM THE SPEED SAFETY CAMERAS
INSTALLED AT 33 LOCATIONS IN THE CITY EARLIER THIS YEAR.
LAST WEEK I JOINED WALK US FROM THE EREKA VALLEY NEIGHBORHOOD
ASSOCIATION, MY DISTRICT TO CELEBRATE THE 15% DECREASE
IN SPEEDING EVENTS DURING THE FIRST TWO MONTHS OF OPERATION
OF THE CAMERA ON MARKET BETWEEN DANVERS AND DOUGLAS WHERE
MULTIPLE HOMES HAD BEEN CRASHED INTO OVER THE YEARS AND CARS AS
WELL PARKED ON THE SIDE OF THE STREET OVER ALL THE CORRIDORS
WHERE CAMERAS HAVE BEEN INSTALLED HAVE SEEN AN AVERAGE
30% REDUCTION IN SPEEDING WITH THE BIGGEST CHANGES ON HIGH
VOLUME CORRIDORS LIKE FULTON WHICH SAW A 63% DECREASE OVER
13 WEEKS. GENEVA WHICH SAW A 45% DECREASE
OVER EIGHT WEEKS AND BAYSHORE BOULEVARD WHICH SAW A 40%
DECREASE OVER SEVEN WEEKS. >> NOW THIS IS NOT TO SAY THAT
THERE'S NOT MORE WORK TO DO. THERE'S LOTS S.F. PD'S TRAFFIC
COMPANY REMAINS WOEFULLY UNDERSTAFFED AND ENFORCEMENT
LEVELS EVEN WITH THE INCREASES I DESCRIBED REMAIN FAR BELOW
2014 LEVELS. AND ALTHOUGH WE'RE SEEING
IMPROVEMENTS IN VEHICLE SPEEDS IN LOCATIONS WHERE WE HAVE BEEN
ABLE TO INSTALL SPEED CAMERAS, STATE LAW CURRENTLY PREVENTS US
FROM WIDER USE OF THAT TECHNOLOGY.
NONETHELESS IT'S IMPORTANT TO ACKNOWLEDGE PROGRESS WHERE WE
SEE IT AND IT DOES SEEM LIKE WE FINALLY HAVE SOME CLEAR SIGNS
OF PROGRESS. AT THIS HEARING WE'RE GOING TO
EXPLORE HOW TO BUILD ON THAT PROGRESS OVER THE LAST DECADE
AS THE MTA HAS INSTALLED TRAFFIC CALMING INFRASTRUCTURE
IMPROVEMENTS ACROSS THE CITY AND BUT FRANKLY WITHOUT THE
IMPROVEMENTS IN TRAFFIC FATALITY AND SEVERE INJURY DATA
THAT WE WOULD ALL LIKE TO SEE. AND THANK YOU SUPERVISOR MELGAR
FOR YOUR MELGAR FOR YOUR LEADERSHIP AND CONGRATULATIONS
ON ON YOUR RESOLUTION THAT WE JUST PASSED.
I BELIEVE THAT ENFORCEMENT HAS BEEN THE MISSING ELEMENT
AND I'M HOPEFUL THAT AS WE FINALLY ARE ABLE TO ADD
INCREASED ENFORCEMENT TO THE MIX, WE WILL FINALLY BE ABLE TO
MOVE OR AT LEAST TO APPROACH OUR GOAL OF ZERO TRAFFIC
FATALITIES AND SEVERE INJURIES. AS I'VE SAID BEFORE, WE CAN
AND SHOULD USE EVERY TOOL THAT WE CAN TO PROTECT THE LIVES OF
PEDESTRIANS AND MAKE OUR STREETS SAFER FOR OUR MOST
VULNERABLE RESIDENTS AND IN MY VIEW ENFORCEMENT MUST BE IN THE
TOOLBOX. SECONDLY, COLLEAGUES TODAY I'M
INTRODUCING AN ORDINANCE TO GIVE THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
THE SAME BEHEST AND PAYMENT WAIVER AUTHORITY ALREADY
AVAILABLE TO DEPARTMENTS. THE MAYOR AND OTHER ELECTED
OFFICIALS. IN 2022 VOTERS PASSED
PROPOSITION E WHICH PROHIBITED ELECTED OFFICIALS, DEPARTMENT
HEADS, COMMISSIONERS AND DESIGNATED EMPLOYEES FROM
SOLICITING DONATIONS FROM INTERESTED PARTIES UNLESS THEY
OBTAINED FROM THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS A HAS PAYMENT
WAIVER BASED ON A BOARD FINDING THAT THE WAIVER WOULD BE IN THE
BEST INTEREST OF THE PUBLIC. >> IN THE THREE YEARS SINCE
POPPY'S PASSAGE THIS BOARD HAS BEEN ASKED FOR AND ALLOWED AS
DID PAYMENT WAIVERS TO PROCURE FIRE TRUCKS FOR THE SAN
FRANCISCO FIRE DEPARTMENT, EXPAND SHELTER BEDS, DELIVER
IMMIGRANT LEGAL SERVICES, ADDRESS THE FENTANYL CRISIS
AND THE LIST GOES ON AND ON. HOWEVER, FOR REASONS THAT ARE
NOT CLEAR TO ME HAVE NEVER BEEN CLEAR TO ME PROP E DOES NOT
ALLOW MEMBERS OF THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS TO SEEK OR OBTAIN
SUCH WAIVERS. IN MY VIEW THAT EXCLUSION MAKES
NO SENSE. SUPERVISORS ARE OFTEN THE
CLOSEST TO OUR COMMUNITIES. WE HEAR DIRECTLY FROM NEIGHBORS
AND COMMUNITY ORGANIZATIONS ABOUT THEIR NEEDS AND WE'RE
WELL-POSITIONED TO HELP DIRECT PHILANTHROPIC PHILANTHROPIC
DOLLARS TOWARD URGENT AND EMERGING PRIORITIES.
YET AMONG ELECTED AND APPOINTED OFFICIALS WE ARE AGAIN UNIQUELY
EXCLUDED FROM THE POSSIBILITY OF A WAIVER NO MATTER THE
PUBLIC INTEREST THAT MIGHT BE SERVED.
HAPPILY, THIS EXCLUSION CAN BE CHANGED BY A TWO THIRDS VOTE OF
THIS BOARD AND CONCURRENCE BY THE ETHICS COMMISSION.
AND AS THE CITY IS ENTERING A PERIOD OF SUSTAINED BUDGETARY
CHALLENGES WITH A HOSTILE FEDERAL ADMINISTRATION
THREATENING THE FUNDING OF IMPORTANT LOCAL PRIORITIES, I
THINK IT IS TIME TO PURSUE THAT CHANGE.
THE ORDINANCE I'M INTRODUCING TODAY WOULD ALLOW THE BOARD TO
GRANT WAIVERS TO SUPERVISORS BASED ON THE SAME FINDING OF
PUBLIC INTEREST CURRENTLY USED TO JUSTIFY WAIVERS FOR OTHER
ELECTED OFFICIALS. ANY WAIVER RESOLUTION WOULD
IDENTIFY POTENTIAL DONORS WHEN KNOWN DESCRIBED THE PURPOSE OF
THIS LIST SOLICITATIONS AND EXPLAIN HOW THE WAIVER IS
IN THE PUBLIC INTEREST. WAIVERS FOR SUPERVISORS WOULD
REMAIN SUBJECT TO THE SAME SCRUTINY AND ACCOUNTABILITY
STANDARDS AS EVERY OTHER BASED ON PAYMENT WAIVER.
I WANT TO THANK MELANIE MATHESON IN MY OFFICE FOR ALL
HER WORK ON THIS ORDINANCE. DIRECTOR PATRICK FORD
AND MICHAEL CANNING AT THE ETHICS COMMISSION AND DEPUTY
CITY ATTORNEYS BRAD RUSSI AND KATHLEEN REYES FOR THEIR
WORK ON THE LEGISLATION. AND I SEE WE HAVE I HAVE
MANAGED TO TAKE US PAST 230. SO MADAM CLERK, CAN YOU PLEASE
CALL OUR 230 SPECIAL ORDER? >> YES.
TODAY'S 230 SPECIAL ORDER IS A RECOGNITION OF COMMENDATIONS.
>> ALL RIGHT. AND FIRST UP DISTRICT FIVE
SUPERVISOR MAHMUD. >> COLLEAGUES IN RECOGNITION OF
SEPTEMBER BEING RECOVERY MONTH. >> I'M PLEASED TO RECOGNIZE
RICHARD A REMARKABLE COMMUNITY LEADER, AUTHOR AND TIRELESS
ADVOCATE FOR RECOVERY IN SAN FRANCISCO, ESPECIALLY IN THE
TENDERLOIN. >> RICHARD, WHY DON'T YOU COME
TO THE PODIUM? >> FOR NEARLY THREE DECADES,
RICHARD HAS WORKED TO ENSURE THAT THE VOICES OF THOSE TOO
OFTEN LEFT OUT INDIVIDUALS EXPERIENCING HOMELESSNESS THOSE
LIVING WITH ADDICTION AND THOSE RETURNING FROM INCARCERATION
ARE NOT JUST HEARD BUT SEEN AND CONNECTED TO THE
INSTITUTIONS THAT SHAPE PUBLIC POLICY.
HEALTH CARE AND HOUSING IN OUR CITY.
RICHARD BEGAN HIS WORK IN 1996 AT ST ANTHONY'S FOUNDATION
WHERE HE FIRST COMMITTED HIMSELF TO SERVICE.
>> HE LATER JOINED THE HATE ASHBURY FREE CLINICS ADVANCING
FROM SUBSTANCE ABUSE COUNSELOR TO CENTER MANAGER FOR ITS
RESIDENTIAL PROGRAMS ON TREASURE ISLAND.
>> IN 2010 HE BEGAN MANAGING THE ROADS TO RECOVERY PROGRAM
FOR CENTREPOINT AT COUNTY JAIL NUMBER FIVE.
SUPPORTING INDIVIDUALS ON THEIR PATH FROM INCARCERATION TO
REINTEGRATION. AND LATER JOINING THE
TENDERLOIN HOUSING CLINIC AS THE DIRECTOR OF RECOVERY
SERVICES. RICHARD HAS ALSO SHARED HIS
STORY WITH THE WORLD BY AUTHORING HIS BOOK RECOVERING
FROM THE GAME AND CO-FOUNDING BAD BROTHERS AGAINST DRUG
DEATHS, AN ORGANIZATION DEDICATED TO SAVING LIVES
AND BUILDING STRONGER PATHWAYS TO RECOVERY.
>> SEVERAL COMMUNITY MEMBERS REACHED OUT TO US TO SHARE
THEIR WORDS OF PRAISE FOR RICHARD AS WELL.
RUDY CORPUS OF UNITED PLAYERS PUT IT RICHARD IS ONE OF GOD'S
SOLDIERS. HE MOVES WITH THE SPIRIT OF
LOVE IN ALL HE DOES AND THE MAYOR OF THE TENDERLOIN, DALE
SEYMOUR SAID IT BEST WHEN HE SHARED THAT RICHARD BEALE IS
THE TENDERLOINS CHAMPION OF RECOVERY.
>> HE IS TRULY BOOTS ON THE GROUND.
IF WE HAD HEARD IF WE HAD MORE RICHARD BEALES IN OUR COMMUNITY
WE WOULD BE IN BETTER SHAPE. >> WITH 30 YEARS OF SOBRIETY
UNDER HIS BELT, RICHARD IS A LIVING TESTAMENT TO WHAT'S
POSSIBLE WHEN WE CHOOSE HOPE. HE IS SOMEONE WHO BUILDS
BRIDGES FROM ADDICTION TO ADVOCACY AND FROM PAIN TO
PURPOSE. >> RICHARD, THANK YOU FOR
CONTINUING TO SHOW UP FOR OUR COMMUNITIES DAY IN, DAY OUT
AND FOR HELPING SO MANY SAN FRANCISCANS FIND THEIR WAY
FORWARD. >> YOUR WORK STRENGTHENS NOT
ONLY THE TENDERLOIN BUT THE ENTIRE FABRIC OF SAN FRANCISCO
. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU. AND RICHARD, BEFORE YOU SPEAK,
I JUST WANT TO PILE ON IF IF SUPERVISOR DORSEY WERE HERE, I
KNOW HE WOULD. I KNOW HE'S BUMMED THAT HE'S
NOT BECAUSE HE WOULD HE WOULD ALSO WANT TO ADD ON TO THIS.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD FOR.
FOR THIS COMMENDATION. I FEEL LIKE I HAVE, YOU KNOW,
BEEN A WITNESS OVER THESE LAST SEVEN YEARS OF A REAL
TRANSFORMATION IN THE CONVERSATION ABOUT RECOVERY
AND HOW WE PRIORITIZE RECOVERY AS A CITY THAT HAS IMPACTED
POLICY IN DEEP WAYS AND HAS IMPACTED OUR DEPARTMENT OF
PUBLIC HEALTH. AND I THINK RICHARD BEALE HAS
BEEN A BIG PART OF THAT AND IT'S IT'S BEEN A JOY REALLY
TO SEE FOLKS IN THE RECOVERY COMMUNITY BE ABLE TO COME
FORWARD, ORGANIZE THEMSELVES AND DEMAND MORE AND BETTER THAN
WHAT THE CITY HAD BEEN OFFERING AND TO ASK THE CITY TO HAVE
HIGHER ASPIRATIONS FOR PEOPLE WHO USE DRUGS TO TO GET
SOMETHING BETTER THAN LIFELONG AS LONG AS THAT MAY BE
MAINTENANCE BUT ACTUALLY RECOVERY AND SOBRIETY AND I
THINK I JUST WANT TO COMMEND YOU.
I FEEL LIKE I'VE LEARNED SO MUCH FROM YOU AND I THINK THIS
IS INCREDIBLY WELL DESERVED. SO GOOD FOR YOU, RICHARD BEALE
AND HAPPY AGAIN. HAPPY 30TH SOBER VERSITY.
>> SO WE'RE VERY SORRY. >> YEAH.
GOOD AFTERNOON. FIRST I WANT TO SAY YOU KNOW, I
WANT TO OPEN UP WITH THE SERENITY PRAYER GUY.
GRANT ME THE SERENITY TO ACCEPT THE THINGS THAT I CANNOT
CHANGE. THE COURAGE TO CHANGE THE
THINGS THAT I CAN AND THE WISDOM TO KNOW THE DIFFERENCE.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT HE MEANT AND HOW POWERFUL THAT PRAYER
WAS GOING TO HAVE ON MY LIFE. YOU YOU KNOW, I WANT TO THANK
PRESIDENT TO BE SUPERVISORS, DISTINGUISHED GUESTS, MY
FRIENDS AND FAMILY AND COMMUNITY PARTNERS.
I STAND BEFORE YOU TODAY WITH THE HEART FULL OF GRATITUDE TO
BE RECOGNIZED BY THE SAN FRANCISCO BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
FOR MY WORK WITH UNHOUSED RECOVERY AND REENTRY COMMUNITY
OVER THE LAST 30 YEARS IS A PROFOUND HONOR.
WHEN I FIRST BEGAN THIS JOURNEY IT WAS NEVER ABOUT AWARDS OR
RECOGNITION. IT WAS ABOUT SURVIVAL,
TRANSFORMATION AND SERVICE. I KNOW FIRSTHAND THE STRUGGLES
OF ADDICTION, HOMELESSNESS AND INCARCERATION.
I ALSO KNOW THE POWER OF RECOVERY COMMUNITY IS SECOND
CHANCES. MY LIFE HAS BEEN A BLESSED
JOURNEY BECAUSE OF OTHERS BELIEVED IN ME WHEN I COULDN'T
BELIEVE IN MYSELF. IT HAS BEEN MY MISSION EVER
SINCE TO GIVE THAT SAME HOPE AND OPPORTUNITY TO OTHERS.
>> OVER THREE DECADES I'VE HAD THE PRIVILEGE OF WALKING
ALONGSIDE THOUSANDS OF MEN AND WOMEN HELPING THEM FIND
HOUSING, RECONNECT THEM WITH THEIR FAMILIES INTO RECOVERY
AND REBUILD THEIR LIVES. THIS WORK HAS ONLY BEEN
POSSIBLE BECAUSE OF THE MANY ORGANIZATIONS SINCE ADVOCATES
AND CITY PARTNERS WHO STAND ON THE FRONT LINES EVERY DAY.
>> SO THIS RECOGNITION IS NOT MINE ALONE.
IT BELONGS TO ALL OF US WHO BELIEVE THAT RECOVERY IS
POSSIBLE. THAT DIGNITY IS NON-NEGOTIABLE
AND THAT EVERY LIFE HAS VALUE. >> SAN FRANCISCO IS A CITY OF
RESILIENCE, COMPASSION AND INNOVATION.
TOGETHER WE CAN CONTINUE TO BUILD PATHWAYS FOR THOSE WHO
ARE STRUGGLING. BREAK CYCLES OF HOMELESS
AND ADDICTION AND CREATE SPACES WHERE HEALING IS POSSIBLE.
AS THE AMBASSADOR FOR RECOVERY I AM GRATEFUL TO BE PART OF THE
RECOVERY FIRST MOVEMENT HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
WE NEED MORE TREATMENT BEDS. WE NEED DRUG FREE HOUSING
INCLUDING DRUG FREE PERMANENT SUPPORTIVE HOUSING.
BUT MOST OF ALL WE NEED TO SHUT DOWN THESE OPEN AIR DRUG
MARKETS. AND TO DO THIS WE NEED TO WORK
TOGETHER. IT WOULD TAKE A COLLECTIVE
EFFORT. SO TO THE BOARD OF SUPERVISORS
THANK YOU FOR LIFTING UP THIS WORK AND AFFIRMING THAT
RECOVERY HOUSING AND REENTRY SERVICES MATTER TO MY COMMUNITY
MY COLLEAGUES, MY FAMILY, MY FRIENDS.
THANK YOU FOR ALWAYS STANDING WITH ME ON THIS JOURNEY.
I ACCEPT THIS RECOGNITION OF THOSE WHO HAVE WE HAVE LOST
AND THOSE STILL FIGHTING AND THOSE WHO REMIND US EVERY
DAY THAT CHANGE IS POSSIBLE. THANK YOU AND GOD BLESS
. >> GROUP PHOTO OUTSIDE JOE
AND WE WERE GOING TO HAVE A DISTRICT SIX COMMENDATION BUT
SUPERVISOR DORSEY IS NOT ABLE TO DO THAT AND I THINK DISTRICT
NINE WERE NOT DOING RIGHT. OKAY SO WITH THAT MADAM CLERK,
WHY DON'T WE GO BACK TO ROLLCALL?
>> YES. NEXT UP ON ROLL CALL IS
SUPERVISOR MELGAR. >> THANK YOU SO MUCH, MADAM
CLERK. COLLEAGUES I AM PROUD TO
INTRODUCE ALONG WITH PRESIDENT MANDELL MEN SUPERVISORS CHEN
FIELDER, CHERYL SAUDER, WALTON DORSEY AND GADO.
I RESOLUTION PROCLAIMING SEPTEMBER 27TH THROUGH OCTOBER
FIFTH AS GOOD NEIGHBOR WEEK IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO A NEIGHBOR IS NOT JUST SOMEONE WHO LIVES NEXT
DOOR OR IN YOUR COMMUNITY. THEY ARE ACTIVE PARTICIPANTS
IN FOSTERING, UNDERSTANDING, RESPECT AND A SENSE OF
BELONGING FOR ALL RESIDENTS. >> NATIONAL GOOD NEIGHBOR WEEK
IS OBSERVED ON SEPTEMBER 28TH AND WAS PROCLAIMED BY PRESIDENT
JIMMY CARTER IN 1978 AND IS CELEBRATED IS CELEBRATE IT
IN CITIES ACROSS THE COUNTRY AN INCLUSIVE CITY LIKE OURS
ALREADY EMBODIES THE SPIRIT OF GOOD NEIGHBOR DAY THROUGH
ENCOURAGING SIMPLE ACTS OF KINDNESS AND COMMUNITY
CONNECTION IN ALL NEIGHBORHOODS.
BUT WE COULD ALWAYS DO MORE TO CELEBRATE HOW EVERYDAY
RESIDENTS CONTRIBUTE TO THE FABRIC OF OUR NEIGHBORHOODS
AND DO MORE TO FOSTER STRONGER BONDS AND BRIDGES.
GOOD NEIGHBOR WEEK AS A PERFECT OPPORTUNITY FOR SAN FRANCISCO
RESIDENTS TO BUILD ON EVERY DAY ACTS OF CARE NEIGHBORS LENDING
A HAND LOOKING OUT FOR ONE ANOTHER AND WORKING TOGETHER TO
BUILD A MORE COMPASSIONATE CITY.
IN 2023 THE US SURGEON GENERAL DECLARED LONELINESS A PUBLIC
HEALTH CRISIS. AND NOW AS WE FACE A SOCIETY
THAT IS GROWING MORE ANXIOUS WITH POLITICAL DIVISIVENESS
AND TOXICITY, WE NEED TO CONNECT WITH EACH OTHER FOR THE
SAKE OF OUR SHARED HUMANITY. SO I AM VERY EXCITED THAT THERE
IS AN AWESOME TEAM OF FOUNDING PARTNERS ORGANIZING THE VERY
FIRST OFFICIAL GOOD NEIGHBOR WEEK HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO
INCLUDING INCLUDING JULIA GATES ,DISTRICT SEVEN RESIDENT AND A
FOUNDER OF COMMUNITY NEWS LAB WHO IS HERE TODAY.
>> PLEASE CHECK OUT W W W DOT S.F. GOOD NEIGHBORHOOD WEEK.ORG
TO LEARN MORE ABOUT THE NOMINATIONS FOR THE GOOD
NEIGHBOR AWARD EVENTS IN YOUR OWN NEIGHBORHOOD INCLUDING
NEIGHBORHOOD CLEANUPS, HACKATHON SCAVENGER HUNTS,
COMMUNITY POTLUCKS GAME DAYS AND MORE HOWEVER YOU CELEBRATE.
>> LET THIS BE A REMINDER TO REACH OUT TO SOMEONE IN YOUR
BLOCK WHO YOU HAVEN'T MET OR CATCH UP WITH A NEIGHBOR YOU
HAVEN'T CHECKED IN ON FOR A WHILE.
LET US MARK THIS WEEK SEPTEMBER 27TH THROUGH OCTOBER 5TH OF
GOOD NEIGHBOR WEEK AS A WAY TO CELEBRATE ALL THE WONDERFUL
RESIDENTS WHO BRING JOY AND EMPATHY IN SMALL WAYS
AND BIG WAYS TO OUR CITY. THE REST I SUBMIT.
THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR MELGAR.
SUPERVISOR SAUTER THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR CHERYL.
>> THANK YOU. BEFORE I START I JUST WANTED TO
THANK SUPERVISOR MELGAR FOR INTRODUCING THE STREET SAFETY
ACT. I THINK IT IS A CRITICAL NEXT
STEP IN OUR JOURNEY TO ENSURING THE STREETS ARE SAFE AND I
REALLY LOOK FORWARD TO WORKING WITH YOU AND WITH THE REST OF
THE BOARD ON THAT AS WELL AS SIDEWALK SAFETY AND AS WELL AS
INCREASED CONGESTION AS WE THINK ABOUT THE FUTURE OF
TRANSPORTATION IN THE CITY. THE WORLD AROUND US IS
CHANGING. AVS ARE GROWING.
>> CONGESTION IS UP. RIDESHARES ARE UP.
COMMUTERS ARE DOWN. YET THE NUMBER OF CARS WE HAVE
ON OUR STREETS IS HIGHER THAN EVER.
WE NEED TO BE ROBUST IN OUR THINKING TO INCREASE SAFETY TO
MAKE SURE THAT FAMILIES ON ALL MODES OF TRANSPORTATION WHETHER
IT'S CARS OR PUBLIC TRAINS OR BIKES CAN GET AROUND SMOOTHLY.
THIS IS GOING TO TAKE AN ENORMOUS AMOUNT OF WORK.
ALL OF US TOGETHER I HOPE AND I JUST WANT TO THANK YOU FOR
MOVING US FORWARD ON THAT FIRST STEP FOR THIS NEXT DECADE WHICH
I THINK WE ALL HOPE WILL BE A SAFER, SMOOTHER DECADE THAN THE
ONE PASSED. >> SECOND, I'M PROUD TO
INTRODUCE A RESOLUTION RECOGNIZING SEPTEMBER 27TH,
2025 AS TUCSON FESTIVAL DAY. >> HERE IN SAN FRANCISCO,
CUSACK OFTEN CALLED KOREAN THANKSGIVING IS ONE OF THE MOST
IMPORTANT HOLIDAYS IN KOREAN CULTURE CELEBRATING THE
HARVEST, HONORING ANCESTORS AND SHARING TRADITIONS WITH
LOVED ONES WITH ROOTS GOING BACK MORE THAN 2000 YEARS.
IT REMAINS A VIBRANT HOLIDAY FOR KOREANS
AND KOREAN-AMERICANS WORLDWIDE .
SAN FRANCISCO HAS LONG BEEN A CENTER OF KOREAN AMERICAN
HISTORY. THE FIRST KOREAN DIPLOMATIC
DELEGATION TO THE U.S. ARRIVED HERE IN 1883 AND IN 1909 THE
KOREAN NATIONALISTS ASSOCIATION WAS FOUNDED IN OUR CITY.
>> GUIDING A COMMUNITY THAT HAS MADE IMMEASURABLE CONTRIBUTIONS
EVER SINCE. >> I ALSO WANT TO EXPRESS MY
GRATITUDE TO FORMER SUPERVISOR KATHRYN STEFANI WHO BEGAN THE
TRADITION OF RECOGNIZING CHU SOC HERE AT CITY HALL AND LAID
THE FOUNDATION FOR US TO CONTINUE HONORING THIS
IMPORTANT CULTURAL CELEBRATION. NOW THIS YEAR IS ESPECIALLY
MEANINGFUL AS WE MARK THE 80TH ANNIVERSARY OF KOREA'S
LIBERATION DAY AND THE 50TH ANNIVERSARY OF THE KOREAN
CENTER INC. FOR FIVE DECADES THE CENTER HAS PRESERVED KOREAN
HERITAGE PROVIDED CRITICAL SERVICES AND HOSTED THE BAY
AREA. CHU SUK FESTIVAL NOW IN ITS
SEVENTH YEAR AT THE PRESIDIO. >> I WANT TO THANK THE KOREAN
CENTER AND THE KOREAN-AMERICAN COMMUNITY FOR THEIR LEADERSHIP
AND CONTRIBUTIONS TO SAN FRANCISCO AND PERHAPS ABOVE ALL
I ENCOURAGE EVERYBODY TO ATTEND THE FESTIVAL ON SEPTEMBER 27TH
AT THE MAIN LAWN AT THE PRESIDIO.
IT'S GOING TO BE A FABULOUS DAY FOR FAMILIES AND FOR EVERYBODY
AND FRANKLY I CAN'T WAIT AND I HOPE TO SEE ALL OF YOU THERE.
>> THE REST I SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR SHERYL SUPERVISOR WALTON THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
COLLEAGUES TODAY I HAVE AND MORE AM TO HONOR THE LIFE
AND LEGACY OF JACQUELINE. KNOWN AS JACKIE COHEN, A PROUD
NATIVE SAN FRANCISCAN AND BELOVED MEMBER OF THE
BAYVIEW HUNTERS POINT COMMUNITY WHERE SHE LIVED FOR OVER 40
YEARS. JACKIE BEGAN HER CAREER AS A
PRESCHOOL TEACHER IN THE SAN FRANCISCO UNIFIED SCHOOL
DISTRICT'S EARLY EDUCATION DEPARTMENT.
LATER SHE BECAME A SCHOOL BUS DRIVER IN 1989, SAFELY
TRANSPORTING HUNDREDS OF S.F. USD STUDENTS ACROSS THE CITY.
IN 1999, JACKIE CO-FOUNDED 100% COLLEGE PREP AND THE BAYVIEW
ASSOCIATION FOR YOUTH ORGANIZATIONS THAT HAVE SINCE
BECOME PILLARS IN DISTRICT TEN. THROUGH HER TIRELESS LEADERSHIP
,SHE HELPED HUNDREDS OF YOUNG PEOPLE ACCESS HIGHER EDUCATION
PREPARING THEM NOT ONLY FOR COLLEGE BUT ALSO FOR CAREERS
AND LIFELONG SUCCESS. JACKIE WAS A FIERCE ADVOCATE
FOR YOUTH AND PARENT ENGAGEMENT.
SHE CREATED SPACES FOR LEARNING AND CONNECTION, INCLUDING THE
CLASS RAISING A CHILD IN THE HIP HOP GENERATION AND A
DYNAMIC YOU FLED MUSICAL SHOWCASE AT THE RUTH WILLIAMS
BAYVIEW OPERA HOUSE. HER SERVICE EXTENDED WELL
BEYOND THESE PROGRAMS. JACKIE ALSO GAVE HER TIME
IN LEADERSHIP ON COMMUNITY BOARDS INCLUDING THE BAYVIEW
CHC ASSOCIATION FOR YOUTH, THE RUTH WILLIAMS BAYVIEW OPERA
HOUSE AND AS THE SAN FRANCISCO FOUNDATION CASTLING FELLOW.
JACKIE'S PASSION CREATIVITY AND DEDICATION LEFT A LASTING
MARK ON OUR CITY. SHE UPLIFTED YOUNG PEOPLE,
EMPOWERED PARENTS AND STRENGTHEN THE CULTURAL
AND EDUCATIONAL FABRIC OF BAYVIEW HUNTERS POINT.
I WANT TO EXTEND MY DEEPEST CONDOLENCES TO HER FAMILY,
FRIENDS AND COLLEAGUES. WE COMMEND JACKIE COHEN FOR HER
DECADES OF SERVICE AND UNWAVERING COMMITMENT TO
SAN FRANCISCO YOUTH AND FAMILIES.
HER LEGACY WILL LIVE ON THROUGH EVERY STUDENT WHO DARED TO
DREAM OF COLLEGE. EVERY PARENT SHE INSPIRED
AND EVERY LIFE SHE TOUCHED. >> THE REST I SUBMIT.
>> THANK YOU. SUPERVISOR WALTON.
SUPERVISOR CHAN. THANK YOU, SUPERVISOR CHEN.
THANK YOU. >> SUPERVISOR AND GUARDIAN.
THANK YOU. TODAY I ASK THAT WE ADJOURN
THIS MEETING IN MEMORY OF KWANG QUIN.
A BELOVED COMMUNITY AMBASSADOR IN THE OUTER SUNSET.
OUR OFFICE IS DEEPLY SADDENED BY HIS PASSING ON JULY 24TH
IN SAN FRANCISCO SURROUNDED BY HIS FAMILY.
HE WAS 60 YEARS OLD. BORN IN VIETNAM IN 1965, KWANG
DEVOTED HIS LIFE TO SERVICE COMPASSION AND COMMUNITY.
FOR NEARLY A DECADE HE SERVED AS A COMMUNITY AMBASSADOR
IN BOTH DISTRICT TEN AND THE OUTER SUNSET WHERE HE BECAME A
FAMILIAR AND TRUSTED PRESENCE AND SOMEONE WHO MADE PEOPLE
FEEL SAFE, SEEN AND SUPPORTED IN HIS ROLE AS A COMMUNITY
AMBASSADOR AT OCA. KWAN CONDUCTED WELLNESS CHECKS
FOR INDIVIDUALS IN PUBLIC SPACES PROVIDED A SAFETY
PRESENCE NEAR SCHOOLS AND REGULARLY ESCORTED STUDENTS
TO AND FROM PUBLIC OUTINGS. HE OFFERED DIRECTIONS TO HELP
PEOPLE FIND THEIR WAY AND REFERRED THOSE IN NEED OF
VITAL CITY SERVICES AND RESOURCES.
HE MADE 311 REPORTS EMERGENCY CALLS AND DID WHATEVER IT WAS
NEEDED TO KEEP HIS COMMUNITY SAFE AND CARED FOR.
KWANG WAS ESPECIALLY KNOWN FOR HIS KIND INTERACTIONS
INTERACTIONS WITH CHILDREN, THE SUPPORT HE GAVE TO ELDERS
AND MERCHANTS AND THE CALM STRENGTH HE BROUGHT TO EVERY
SITUATION. HUANG'S FRIENDS REMEMBER THE
MEALS HE COOKED, THE THINGS HE QUIETLY REPAIRED, THE RIDES HE
OFFERED AND THE COUNTLESS WAYS HE CARED FOR THOSE AROUND HIM.
MUSIC WAS ONE OF HIS GREAT JOYS AND HIS GUITAR BROUGHT HIM
PEACE AND COMFORT AND DID THE SAME FOR THOSE LUCKY ENOUGH TO
HEAR HIM PLAY. KWANG IS SURVIVED BY HIS LOVING
WIFE, HIS SON ALEX AND HIS DAUGHTER TIFFANY WHO WILL CARRY
ON HIS MEMORY WITH STRENGTH AND LOVE.
HE IS ALSO SURVIVED BY EIGHT OF HIS 11 SIBLINGS AS WELL AS MANY
FRIENDS, COWORKERS AND COMMUNITY MEMBERS WHOSE
LIVES WERE TOUCHED BY HIS KINDNESS.
HIS LEGACY LIVES ON IN THE MANY PEOPLE HE HELPED PROTECTED
AND LOVED. HIS TEAM AND FELLOW AMBASSADORS
ARE WITH US IN THE CHAMBER TODAY TO REMEMBER THE IMPACT HE
HAD ON EACH OF THEM AND OUR COMMUNITY AND THE REST I
SUBMIT. >> THANK YOU SUPERVISOR
AND GUARDIAN. SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANK YOU.
SUPERVISOR MAHMOOD. THANK YOU.
MR. PRESIDENT, I CAN CONCLUDE THE ROLL CALL FOR
INTRODUCTIONS. >> ALL RIGHT, LET'S GO TO
PUBLIC COMMENT. >> AT THIS TIME THE BOARD
WELCOMES YOUR PUBLIC COMMENT. PLEASE LINE UP TO YOUR RIGHT
HAND SIDE OF THE CHAMBER ALONG THE CURTAINS.
YOU MAY SPEAK TO ITEM 32 THROUGH 37 FOR ADOPTION WITHOUT
COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA. GENERAL MATTERS THAT ARE NOT ON
TODAY'S PUBLISHED AGENDA BUT WITHIN THE BOARD'S SUBJECT
MATTER JURISDICTION. ALL OTHER AGENDA CONDUCT.
ALL OTHER AGENDA CONTENT WILL HAVE BEEN REPORTED OUT TO THE
BOARD BY AN APPROPRIATE COMMITTEE WHERE THE PUBLIC
COMMENT REQUIREMENT OCCURRED. WILL THE FIRST SPEAKER PLEASE
COME FORWARD? YOU'LL HAVE TWO MINUTES.
>> HELLO. >> HI SUPERVISORS.
I'M JULIA CARESS THE FOUNDER OF SAN FRANCISCO GOOD NEIGHBOR
WEEK AND ONE OF THE USF NONPROFIT INNOVATORS THIS YEAR.
THIS IS OUR FIRST YEAR IN SAN FRANCISCO CELEBRATING NATIONAL
GOOD NEIGHBOR DAY A HOLIDAY THAT AS SUPERVISOR MELGAR SAID
JIMMY CARTER STARTED IN THE 70S TO ELEVATE EVERYDAY ACTS OF
KINDNESS AND OUR COMMUNITIES WILL BE CELEBRATING IT THE LAST
WEEK OF SEPTEMBER EVERY YEAR. I WANT TO SHARE THREE QUICK
THINGS AN UPDATE ON THE GOOD NEIGHBOR AWARDS, AN UPDATE ON
THE EVENTS CALENDAR AND PLANS FOR NEXT YEAR ON THE GOOD
NEIGHBOR AWARDS. THE NOMINATION DEADLINE WAS
LAST WEEK AND I EXTENDED IT FOR A FEW NEIGHBORHOODS WHO ASKED
ME FOR A FEW MORE DAYS TO GET THEIR NOMINATIONS IN.
WE ALREADY HAVE OVER 160 NOMINEES ACROSS ALL 11
DISTRICTS. I WANT TO THANK ALL OF YOU
AND YOUR STAFF FOR HELPING PROMOTE THE NOMINATION FORM
IN YOUR EMAIL NEWSLETTERS AND ON SOCIAL MEDIA.
I CAN'T WAIT FOR YOU TO SEE THE NOMINEES.
THEY'RE THE MOST HEARTWARMING STORIES MANY OF THEM YOU'VE
PROBABLY HEARD OF AND SOME YOU HAVEN'T.
I KNOW MANY OF YOU REGULARLY OFFER COMMENDATIONS FOR YOUR
RESIDENTS AND THE GOOD NEIGHBOR AWARDS.
GIVE US ANOTHER LAYER FOR THAT IN PARTNERSHIP WITH
NEIGHBORHOOD GROUPS WHO ARE COMMITTED TO CELEBRATING THE
WINNERS. >> ON THE EVENTS CALENDAR WE
JUST PUBLISHED THE CALENDAR LAST NIGHT AT S.F. GOOD
NEIGHBOR WEEK.ORG/EVENTS. WE HAVE OVER 40 COMMUNITY
PARTNERS FROM ALL 11 DISTRICTS WHO ARE HELPING US ORGANIZE
EVENTS THIS YEAR FROM NEIGHBORHOOD SCAVENGER HUNTS,
COMMUNITY MUSIC HANGOUTS, BLOCK PARTIES, COFFEES, TRASH PICKUPS
AND THE COUNTRY'S FIRST GOOD NEIGHBOR HACKATHON.
I HAVE EIGHT LOCAL NEWSROOMS ORGANIZING NEIGHBORHOOD
LISTENING SESSIONS. I HAVE NEIGHBORHOOD GROUPS
CELEBRATING THE GOOD NEIGHBOR NOMINEES FROM THEIR COMMUNITIES
AT THEIR EVENTS FOR EXAMPLE THE EUREKA VALLEY NEIGHBORHOOD
ASSOCIATION AND WE'LL BE CELEBRATING THE CASTRO NOMINEES
AT THE CASTRO STREET FAIR ON OCTOBER FIFTH, ETC..
>> THANK YOU FOR PROMOTING AND ATTENDING THESE EVENTS
AND GIVING ACCOMMODATIONS OR CERTIFICATES OF HONOR TO THE
WINNERS. LASTLY PLANS FOR NEXT YEAR.
THIS YEAR'S GOOD NEIGHBOR WEEK IS COMING TOGETHER REALLY
QUICKLY. I ONLY FOUND OUT THIS HOLIDAY
EXISTED A FEW MONTHS AGO SO EVERYONE WHO'S TELLING ME THIS
IS LAST MINUTE IT'S LAST MINUTE FOR ME TOO.
I'VE BEEN TELLING ALL OF OUR COMMUNITY PARTNERS THAT THIS
YEAR IS A LEARNING YEAR FOR US TO TRY SOMETHING AND SEE HOW IT
GOES AND THEN EXPAND IT IN 2026.
>> DOES THAT MEAN IT'S THE END ?
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER PLEASE.
GOOD AFTERNOON. ATTENTION SAN FRANCISCO
MAYOR DANIEL LURIE AND ALL MEMBERS OF SUPPORT FOR A
SUPERVISOR. MY NAME IS DEREK LOCKE.
I'M A CEO OF PROJECT MEADOW, AMBASSADOR OF NINTENDO.
MY JOB IN PARTICULAR THE CEO ROLE WAS GIVEN TO ME MY
REFERRAL BY THE CO-FOUNDERS. I WAS NAMED CEO OF PROJECT
MALLOW BY LOUISA MAC OR SEE BY TITLE.
SHE IS REVERED AS MISS HONG KONG AS AN ACTRESS EMPLOYED BY
TDB. >> SHE GRADUATED WITH A LAW
DEGREE IN 2014 AFTER BEING OF TV FOR FOUR YEARS.
SHE WORKED BRIEFLY IN MCKINSEY. SHE LATER CO-FOUNDED PROJECT
MELLOW AND LEFT ME IN CHARGE PROJECT MELLOW AS A CHARITY
POWERHOUSE WITH CHAT LISTS OF CEO SPONSORSHIP OF ITS MISSION
TO CONNECT THE YOUTH AND CEO THROUGH ACTIVITIES AND DIALOG.
I'M HERE TO PROUDLY ANNOUNCE MY COMMITMENT AS A PIVOTAL ROLE AS
COMPANY OF CEO OF PROJECT MELLOW.
I'M HERE TO COMMIT TO REPORT REGULARLY HERE ON THE STANFORD
SCOPE OF SUPERVISOR WEEKLY ON MY PROGRESS AS CEO.
AND BRIEFLY THIS MESSAGE IS FOR THE REGION IN ALSO KNOWN AS IU
POP STAR OF SOUTH KOREA LAST YEAR THROUGH THE RECOMMENDATION
OF CEO OF UBER DARE CASH HIROSHI.
I MADE A MARRIAGE PROPOSAL AND SHE HAS ACCEPTED MY
ENGAGEMENT. SHE MET WITH ME YESTERDAY AS A
TEAM OF 32,025. I'M HERE TO CONSUMER COMMITMENT
AND HOPEFULLY WILL GET MARRIED AND WE'LL HAVE A GREAT TIME
TOGETHER. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HELLO, MY NAME IS LEAH MCKEEVER.
I HAVE A COUPLE POEMS THAT I WROTE AS A RESIDENT OF SAN
FRANCISCO. NEURO CONVERGENCE FASCISTS DENY
EXISTENCE TO US ALL. LOP OFF YOUR BRAIN ON ALL SIX
SIDES. YOUR CUBE BRAIN CONFORMS
CONVERGES. >> NEURO CONVERGENCE FASCISM
UNHOLY SILENCE CREEPS CAREFULLY RECKLESSLY NOW WRECKING BALL OF
SILENCE DEMOLISHES THOSE THAT STICK OUT THOSE REACHING FOR
THE STARS FOR BETTER LIFE, FOR A BETTER HOME TO ROOTS
AND DEMOLISHES ECCENTRICITY, INTELLECT, CURIOSITY,
COMPASSION EMPATHY DEMOLISHES ASPIRATIONS ENLIGHTENED MINT
HOPE LIFE LISTS RUBBLE CONCRETE DUST CHOKES YOUR LUNGS SURVIVE
AMONG DEMOLISHED DREAMS SKYLINE FLATTENS UNHOLY SILENCE.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> HI, MY NAME IS GABRIELLA AND I AM A STATE DEATH PENALTY
ABOLITION COORDINATOR FOR AMNESTY INTERNATIONAL AND I
WANT TO QUICKLY THANK SUPERVISOR FIELDER AND WALTON
FOR CHAMPIONING THE UNIVERSAL CLEMENCY RESOLUTION THAT I
BELIEVE WILL BE READ A LITTLE BIT LATER TODAY AND I URGE
EVERYONE TO PLEASE CALL ON GOVERNOR NEWSOM TO COMMUTE
EVERYBODY FROM OUR DEATH ROW. WE HAVE THE LARGEST DEATH ROW
IN THE COUNTRY AS WE KNOW AND WE'RE AT 201 EXONEREES.
SO IT IS RACES, CLASSES AND ARBITRARY IN NATURE.
AND I JUST I JUST CAME HERE TO OBSERVE AND THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. >> NEXT SPEAKER AGAIN, I'M
GOING TO SKIP THE PEDOPHILES THING BECAUSE I KNOW THE REASON
WHY. I MEAN THE REASON WHY YOU CAN'T
FAKE BEAUTY IS BECAUSE YOU CAN'T FAKE ANYTHING
IN INTELLIGENCE IN THE FIRST PLACE.
>> SO YOU HAVE NOW TWO OPTIONS. >> YOU EITHER LOOK FOR BEAUTY
AND YOU'RE GOING TO GOING TO ACHIEVE HAPPINESS THEREFORE
JUSTIFY YOUR REASON FOR BEING AT THE END OF YOUR LIFE.
>> YOUR SOUL WILL BE BUCKED OR YOU KEEP WORKING FOR UGLINESS,
DARKNESS AND INTELLIGENCE AND WHEN YOU DIE YOU'RE DONE.
YOU'LL NEVER BE BACK. UNDERSTAND IS CLEAR.
NOW LET'S MAKE A. >> OTHERWISE YOU GET ABSOLUTE
INCOMPETENCE. THAT'S WHERE YOU ARE.
LET'S MAKING THE DECISION NOT TO BE CONFUSED WITH AN
ILLUSION. NO ONE DIES WITH CLOSED EYES.
>> NO ONE INCLUDING BAD ACTORS FROM HOLLYWOOD.
>> OH. SO WHEN SOMETHING EATS YOU, THE
FIRST THING YOU DO IS THIS. WHEN YOU ARE TAKEN BY SURPRISE
THE YOU CERTAINLY DON'T KEEP YOUR EYES CLOSED.
>> YOU UNDERSTAND? >> SO YOU PAY ATTENTION TO WHAT
HAPPENED RECENTLY OR AND YOU REACH A CONCLUSION.
THERE IS SOME EFFECT GOING ON CLEARLY BECAUSE YOU THINK YOU
CAN ACHIEVE YOUR UGLINESS AND BE HAPPY WITH IT.
SORRY IT DOESN'T WORK. THESE ARE THE WORDS OF
EXISTENCE WHICH RELIES ON SELF-CONTROL.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER.
>> GOOD AFTERNOON. BOARD OF SUPERVISORS PRESIDENT.
MADAM AND MY NAME IS RICHARD SD PETERSON AND I'M HERE AGAIN TO
TALK ABOUT PARCEL TAXES BECAUSE NOBODY SEEMS TO KNOW WHAT
PARCEL TAXES REALLY ARE ABOUT. THE BEST I'VE BEEN ABLE TO FIND
SO FAR IS NOT HELP FROM THE CITY BUT FROM SOME PRIVATE
ORGANIZATION CALLED FIX PROP 19.
I HAVEN'T REALLY LOOKED UP PROP 19 BUT WE HAVE TO ASK THE
UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA SAN FRANCISCO HASTINGS TO GIVE US
AN OPINION ON WHAT PARCELS TAXES ARE AND HOW ARE THEY
BASED. IS IT A FLAT TAX RACE PER
PARCEL? IS IT A SQUARE FOOT TAX?
THE TAX CALCULATED BASED ON THE SQUARE FOOTAGE IS A NUMBER OF
UNITS IN A PARTICULAR BUILDING. >> IS IT THE TYPE OF PROPERTY
COMMERCIAL OR PRIVATE? >> NOBODY SEEMS TO REALLY KNOW
THESE QUESTIONS AND EVERYBODY SAYS WELL A PARCEL TAX IS NOT
GOING TO REALLY HURT YOU. YOU KNOW THE WEST SIDE IS THE
ONE THAT IS GOING TO BE SUPPORTING THE DOWNTOWN
INTERESTS FOR A PARCEL TAX. >> AND FOR SOME TO SAY WELL IF
YOU BOUGHT A HOUSE DOWN IN THE WEST SIDE IT'S PROBABLY WORTH
$1 MILLION NOW AND YOU CAN SELL IT, YOU CAN MOVE AND GET OUT OF
HERE AND GET OUT OF THE TOWN, GO WHEREVER YOU WANT.
>> BUT THE REALITY IS PEOPLE WHO BOUGHT HOMES IN SAN
FRANCISCO WANT TO STAY AND THEY'LL DO ANYTHING
IN THEIR POWER TO TRY AND STAY INCLUDING RENTING A ROOM,
GETTING INVOLVED WITH ROOMMATES AND AND AIRBNB AND THAT'S A
GREAT EXAMPLE AIRBNB. SO PLEASE DON'T BE DISINGENUOUS
ABOUT THE PEOPLE TRYING TO STAY IN SAN FRANCISCO AND LIVE THE
REST OF THEIR LIFE HERE. THANK YOU.
>> THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER PERFECT TIMING.
GOOD AFTERNOON BOARD OF SUPERVISORS FOR THE RECORD.
MY NAME IS CHRISTOPHER KLEIN. I ALSO GO BY SERGEANT KLEIN OF
THE UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS. THE LAST NAME IS SCOTT KELLER.
I ANY AND I WANTED TO TALK A LITTLE BIT NOT TOO MUCH ABOUT
THE 70S AND VIOLENCE IN THE 70S PINK FLOYD RELEASED A SONG
AND ANOTHER BRICK IN THE WALL PART TWO AND PORTIONS OF THAT
SONG WERE REDACTED ABOUT FORT CONTROL.
ALSO TALKED ABOUT EDUCATION AND ALSO TALKED ABOUT DARK
SARCASM. >> SO THOUGHT CONTROL IS THE
ABILITY TO USE SURVEILLANCE SYSTEMS, POLITICAL SURVEILLANCE
TO CAUSE POLITICAL VIOLENCE AND WE HAVE SEEN A LOT OF THAT
LATELY AND IT'S GOT TO STOP. I GREW UP IN THE 70S.
IT WAS VERY PAINFUL TO WATCH. IT'S VERY PAINFUL TO WATCH
TODAY. SO THE DARK SARCASM IS WHEN YOU
TALK AT THE POLICE COMMISSION, THE HEALTH COMMISSION, THIS
BODY YOU TALK ABOUT SURVEILLANCE, EVERYBODY TURNS A
BLIND EYE AND EVERYBODY IN THIS ROOM THE HEALTH COMMISSION, THE
POLICE DEPARTMENT, THE POLICE COMMISSION KNOWS WHAT
SURVEILLANCE IS. THE DARK SARCASM IS THAT
EVERYONE IS USING IT FOR POLITICAL SURVEILLANCE TO CAUSE
POLITICAL VIOLENCE AND THAT'S ALL I WANT TO TALK ABOUT
VIOLENCE. WE ALL KNOW THE REPORT WAS
FILED. WE ALL KNOW THE VIOLENCE.
WE ALL SEEN THAT THE NEXT COUPLE OF DAYS, THE NEXT COUPLE
OF WEEKS, COUPLE OF MONTHS. I NEED EVERYBODY IN THIS ROOM
TO FOCUS ON PEACE. THERE'S GOING TO BE A LOT OF
NEGATIVE STORIES OUT THERE. THERE ALREADY HAS BEEN.
WE NEED TO BRING BACK THE PARADES, THE PICNICS, THE
STREET FESTIVALS. EVERYBODY IN THIS ROOM NEEDS TO
WORK TOGETHER TO BRING SAN FRANCISCO BACK TO WHERE IT WAS.
I MOVED TO SAN FRANCISCO BECAUSE OF THAT FEELING.
I FELT WELCOMED HERE. WHEN I FIRST MOVED HERE
IN 2001. >> SO PLEASE WORK TOGETHER.
I KNOW SURVEILLANCE IS A NEED IT NECESSITY BUT YOU HAVE TO
LIMIT IT. YOU CANNOT USE IT 24/7
SPECIALLY ON PEOPLE THAT YOU DON'T DO NOT LIKE YOUR
OPPONENTS AND YOUR DISSIDENTS. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. NEXT SPEAKER IS GOOD EVENING
SUPERVISORS. >> THIS IS ACE WASHINGTON THE
FILLMORE QUARTER AMBASSADOR. I'M JUST HERE SPEAKING ON THE
FILLMORE BUT BEFORE I DO THAT I WOULD JUST LIKE TO SAY I'M NOT
SHOWBOAT LOOKING AT VIDEO. >> I'VE BEEN VIDEOTAPING BOARD
OF SUPERVISORS FOR YEARS. LET ME JUST GIVE YOU A LITTLE
HISTORY. >> THE SAN FRANCISCO GOVERNMENT
CHANNEL NO THERE WASN'T THE FIRST ONE THAT VIDEOTAPE THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS. IT WAS ACE ON THE CASE IN THOSE
BLACK MEDIA PEOPLE. WE WORKED AT CHANNEL 29.
WE CAME DOWN HERE WITH OUR VIDEO CAMERAS, VIDEOTAPED THE
BOARD OF SUPERVISORS BEFORE THERE WAS A GOVERNMENT CHANNEL
BEFORE AND ALL OF THAT BEFORE THERE WAS INTERNET, BEFORE
THERE WAS FACEBOOK AND ALL OF THAT.
WE WE CREATED IT THE BLACK MEDIA ACE OWNED IT GOING CASE.
>> BUT I'M HERE TO TALK ABOUT THE FILLMORE AS YOU MAY OR MAY
NOT KNOW, NEXT WEEK THE MAYOR AND I SUPERVISOR DISTRICT
FIVE WILL BE HAVING A SOMEWHAT I GUESS A MEET AND GREET
SITUATION AT THE FILLMORE FILLMORE WHICH IS WEST BAY
AND WOULD INVITE EVERYBODY TO COME DOWN.
YOU'LL SEE FLIERS AND STUFF LIKE THAT IS TO GREET, MEET
AND TALK TO THE SUPERVISORS IN THE MIRROR WITH PROBLEMS WE
HAVE IN THE WEST CONDITION I'M SO PROUD I'M TICKLED NO NONE
NOT TICKLED PINK. >> I'M TICKLED BLACK RIGHT NOW
. I'M SO HAPPY THAT THIS HAS
TAKEN PLACE IN THIS COME FROM MY LOBBYING FROM THE
SUPERVISORS AND THE MAYOR. I'M PLEASED THAT HAVE GOOD
VIBES AND I THINK IT'S GOING TO BE A GREAT MEETING IS GOING TO
BE SIT DOWN WE GET TO TALK TO THE SUPERVISORS AND THE
MAYOR IN PERSON. I'M NOT SURE HOW THAT'S GOING
TO TURN OUT AND I'M SAYING WHAT IF 100 OR SO PEOPLE SHOW UP,
THEY'RE GOING TO SIT DOWN TALKED INDIVIDUALS AWAY?
I'M NOT SURE WHAT IT IS BUT MY NAME IS ACE AND I'M ON THE
CASE. I'LL BE THERE.
AND I ALSO WANT TO SAY THAT I WILL BE DOING A OUR SECOND TOUR
OUR FIRST TOUR TOOK PLACE THE ON THE 6TH OF SEPTEMBER VERY
SUCCESSFUL BUT OUR SECOND TOUR IS GOING TO BE COMING UP ON
OCTOBER THE 11TH. SO STAY TUNED FOR THAT.
BUT I JUST WANT TO THANK MY SUPERVISOR FOR GETTING TOGETHER
PARTNERSHIP ENDING UP WITH THE MAYOR.
>> I THINK HE CARES AND HE MAY BE A MILLIONAIRE.
>> HE MAY BE A BILLIONAIRE BUT I THINK HE'S STILL STUPID.
>> I'M JUST BEING FACETIOUS, LIVE AND DIRECT AND YOU KNOW
WHAT? >> YOU DON'T HAVE TO ADJUST.
YOU'LL SIT MY NAME IS ACE AND I'M ON THE CASE.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH. I MA'AM DID THANK YOU FOR YOUR
COMMENTS SPEAKER THAT YOU KNOW I ASKED FOR PEOPLE IF THEIR
PREACHER PRAYED FOR CHARLIE KIRK'S FAMILY OR MENTIONED
CHARLIE KIRK. >> YOU KNOW WHEN OUR FIRST
MARTYR WAS KILLED DEVOUT MEN MADE GREAT LAMENTATION, YOU
KNOW, BUT A LOT OF PREACHERS DON'T AREN'T VERY DEVOUT AND I
KNOW I WEPT WHEN JOHN MACARTHUR DIED QUITE A BIT.
BUT YOU KNOW, IT'S REALLY SAD. I GO TO GRACE BIBLE CHURCH
IN HAYWARD AND HE DIDN'T MENTION IT A PEEP.
>> MY WIFE GOES TO COVENANT PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH AND BEFORE
SHE LEFT I SAID YOU KNOW WHAT? I'LL BET YOU THE PREACHER
DOESN'T EVEN MENTION CHARLIE KIRK.
AND I WAS RIGHT AND IT'S REALLY SAD AS THREE OTHER PEOPLE
AND ALL OF THEM SAID NO, THEY DIDN'T EVEN MENTION HIM, DIDN'T
PRAY FOR THEM. I KNOW BENNY JOHNSON SAYS FIND
A NEW CHURCH. YOU KNOW, I KNOW ALL CHRISTIANS
ARE PATHETIC. REALLY THEY ARE.
I AM. I MEAN IT'S ONLY BY GOD'S GRACE
SOME SAY BUT IT DOESN'T NEGATE THE FACT THAT HE WAS MURDERED
AND FOR HIS FAITH AND I AND IT BEARS REPETITION THAT CHRIST
DIED FOR OUR SINS ACCORDING TO THE SCRIPTURES HE WAS BURIED
AND HE WAS RAISED FROM THE DEAD.
THE THIRD DAY ACCORDING TO THE SCRIPTURES DAVID SAID AND BY
THE WAY, DAVID DID NOT LIVE A THOUSAND YEARS AFTER JESUS
CHRIST. HE WAS A THOUSAND YEARS BEFORE
JESUS CHRIST. >> THERE'S A CHRONOLOGY SOLOMON
DID NOT LIVE 950 YEARS AFTER JESUS, RIGHT?
THESE WERE PREDICTIONS PRIOR TO THE FACT AND HE SAID DO NOT
LEAVE MY SOUL IN THE GRAVE. NEITHER WILL THOU SUFFER OR
ALLOW THE HOLY ONE TO SEE CORRUPTION AND JESUS RAISED
FROM THE DEAD HE SHOWED HIMSELF ALIVE FOR 40 DAYS HE ASCENDED
UP AND I FIND IT VERY INTERESTING THAT IT'S BEEN 40
JUBILEES HE'S COMING SOON 911 WAS THE SIXTH TRUMPET IT IS SO
EASY TO UNDERSTAND THE MONTH ALLOW IT HAPPENED IN THE HEBREW
CALENDAR FOR NEXT SPEAKER ARE THERE ANY OTHER INDIVIDUALS WHO
WOULD LIKE TO PROVIDE PUBLIC COMMENT TODAY?
>> PLEASE COME FORWARD NOW. >> GOOD AFTERNOON.
I JUST WANT TO ASSURE THAT THIS IS OPEN JUST TO MAKE A COMMENT
ANY COMMENT? YES.
THANK YOU SO MUCH. I WANT TO BRING IT TO YOUR
ATTENTION. >> I'M A CO-CHAIR OF THE
BEHAVIORAL HEALTH COMMISSION AND ON MARCH 5TH I WENT
IN FRONT OF THE SUNSHINE ORDINANCE TASK FORCE TO ACHIEVE
A THREAD OF EMAILS THAT MADE DEROGATORY COMMENTS TOWARDS ME
THREATS THAT I WAS GOING TO BLOW UP CITY HALL BY A
COMMISSIONER ALEX HUMPHREY THIS HAS NOT BEEN ADDRESSED BY THE
COMMISSION AND WHEN I WENT IN FRONT OF THE SUNSHINE
ORDINANCE TASK FORCE I WAS LAUGHED AT.
>> THEIR MIKES WERE HOT AND SO IT'S ON RECORD AND I WAS
LAUGHED AT. >> THEY TOLD ME TO ADJUDICATE
ANYTHING AND GET HER OUT OF HERE.
HERE SHE IS AGAIN. THIS IS HOW SHE ALWAYS SHOWS UP
. AND THEN THEY LAUGHED
AND PUBLICLY TOLD ME THAT EGGS ARE EXPENSIVE BUT SCRAMBLED
BRAINS ARE IN FRONT OF US. I WAS TOLD BY CLERK REVEAL THAT
YOU RECEIVED THIS LETTER OF REBUTTAL AND I HAVEN'T HEARD A
RESPONSE FROM YOU SO I AM FORMALLY ASKING THAT CHAIR
YANKEE MEMBER PIPER AND CHRIS HYLAND BE UP AND BE QUESTIONED
AND THAT THEIR POSITIONS ARE NOT REAPPOINTED AS A CITY
OFFICIAL UNDER THE BEHAVIORAL HEALTH COMMISSION.
I TAKE IT THE UTMOST IMPORTANCE TO SHOW UP.
I SHOW UP THE SAME ALL THE TIME.
YOU MIGHT NOT ALWAYS LIKE WHAT I HAVE TO SAY BUT MY WHAT I SAY
IS FOR THE PEOPLE, BY THE PEOPLE AND OF THE PEOPLE AND I
STAND FOR THOSE WITH MENTAL HEALTH CHALLENGES AND I REFUSE
TO BE RIDICULED BY THE SUNSHINE ORDINANCE TASK FORCE.
SO I ASK THAT YOU TAKE PROMPT ATTENTION AND PLEASE RESPOND TO
MY REBUTTAL WITH GRATITUDE. >> THANK YOU.
THANK YOU FOR YOUR COMMENTS. SEE NO OTHER SPEAKERS.
MR. PRESIDENT. >> ALL RIGHT.
PUBLIC COMMENT IS NOW CLOSED. MADAM CLERK LET'S GO TO OUR FOR
ADOPTION WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE AGENDA ITEMS 32
THROUGH 37 YES ITEMS 32 TO 37 WERE INTRODUCED FOR ADOPTION
BUT WITHOUT COMMITTEE REFERENCE A UNANIMOUS VOTE IS REQUIRED
FOR ADOPTION OF A RESOLUTION ON FIRST APPEARANCE TODAY.
ALTERNATIVELY, A MEMBER MAY REQUIRE RESOLUTION ON FIRST
APPEARANCE TO GO TO COMMITTEE SUPERVISOR MELGAR I'D LIKE TO
BE ADDED AS A CO-SPONSOR TO 32 PLEASE AND SEVER 34 AT 734.
ALL RIGHT SO ON THE BALANCE OF THE ITEMS, MADAM CLERK, COULD
YOU CALL THE ROLL? >> YES ON ITEMS 3233 3536
AND 37 SUPERVISOR RANDLEMAN RIGHT MANDOLIN I SUPERVISOR
MELGAR MELGAR I SUPERVISOR SADR SADR I SUPERVISOR CHERYL CHERYL
I SUPERVISOR WALTON WALTON I SUPERVISOR CHAN CHAN I
SUPERVISOR CHEN CHEN I SUPERVISOR AND ENGARDIO
AND ENGARDIO I SUPERVISOR FIELDER FIELDER I SUPERVISOR
MAHMOOD MAHMOOD I THERE TONIGHT WITHOUT OBJECTION THE
RESOLUTIONS ARE ADOPTED AND THE MOTION IS APPROVED.
>> MADAM CLERK COULD YOU PLEASE CALL ITEM 34?
>> SO ITEM 34 IS A RESOLUTION TO DECLARE SEPTEMBER 15TH
THROUGH OCTOBER 15TH, 2025 AS LATIN HERITAGE MONTH AND IN THE
CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN FRANCISCO TO HONOR AND TO
CELEBRATE THE CONTRIBUTIONS OF THE LATIN COMMUNITY SUPERVISOR
MELGAR THANK YOU SO MUCH PRESIDENT MANDELL MEN
COLLEAGUES I AM HONORED TO INTRODUCE A RESOLUTION
PROCLAIMING SEPTEMBER 15TH THROUGH OCTOBER 15TH 2025 AS
LATIN HERITAGE MONTH IN THE CITY AND COUNTY OF SAN
FRANCISCO. THIS RESOLUTION IS AN ANNUAL
TRADITION NOW IN THIS YEAR I'M SO PLEASED TO HAVE ANOTHER
LATINA ON THE BOARD TO CELEBRATE WITH AND TO CARRY ON
THIS TRADITION WHEN I'M TERMED OUT.
SO THANK YOU JACKI, FOR ALL YOU DO TO UPLIFT AND INSPIRE OUR
LATIN COMMUNITIES IN SAN FRANCISCO AND FOR CARRYING ON
THE TRADITION OF LEADERSHIP IN OUR COMMUNITY IN NEW
GENERATION. SO I'M SO GRATEFUL THAT YOU'RE
HERE THIS YEAR. I'M ALSO DEVASTATED THAT WE ARE
FORCED TO DEFEND OUR HUMAN RIGHTS AND EXISTENCE AND TO
HAVE TO REMIND OUR FELLOW AMERICANS NOT JUST OF OUR HUMAN
ENTITY BUT OF THE INVALUABLE CONTRIBUTIONS OF LATIN
COMMUNITIES WHETHER GROWING OUR FOOD, CARING FOR OUR CHILDREN,
OUR ELDERS WELCOMING OUR VISITORS, BUILDING OUR HOUSING
GOVERNANCE IN OUR CITY LATIN A PEOPLE TRULY KEEP SAN FRANCISCO
RUNNING. I'M ALSO REMINDED THAT OUR
ECONOMIC RECOVERY CANNOT BE SUCCESSFUL IS NOT POSSIBLE
WITHOUT THE COUNTLESS MEMBERS OF OUR LATIN COMMUNITY HERE
IN SAN FRANCISCO THROUGHOUT THE BAY AREA IN CALIFORNIA AND IN
OUR COUNTRY SAN FRANCISCO HAS ALWAYS BEEN AND ALWAYS WILL BE
THE HAVEN FOR IMMIGRANTS FROM ALL OVER THE WORLD BUT FROM
LATIN AMERICA IT PARTICULARLY FROM OUR FOUNDATION AS A CITY
WHO BRING TRADITIONS AND INNOVATIONS BUILD THIS
COUNTRY FOUND NEW BUSINESSES AND HAVE ALWAYS SEEK NEAR
FREQUENTLY SHAPED THE CITY'S IDENTITY AND GROWTH FOR THE
BETTER DURING A TIME OF HEIGHTENED POLITICAL
UNCERTAINTY OR UNCERTAINTY FOR OUR CITY'S IMMIGRANTS, I AM
CONFIDENT THAT MY COLLEAGUES AND I ALL AGREE THAT SAN
FRANCISCO IS COMMITTED TO PROTECTING AND UPHOLDING THE
RIGHTS OF ALL MEMBERS OF THE LATIN COMMUNITY.
>> THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR YOUR SUPPORT COLLEAGUES.
>> SUPERVISOR FIELDER THANK YOU.
PRESIDENT BENJAMIN THANK YOU SO MUCH TREASURER MELGAR FOR
INTRODUCING THIS RESOLUTION AND FOR LONG BEFORE ME AND YOUR
ROLE AT PLANNING AND IN THE COMMUNITY AT IN THE MISSION FOR
REALLY REPRESENTING ESPECIALLY LATINO WOMEN AND IT'S BEEN AN
HONOR TO SERVE ALONGSIDE YOU THANK YOU FOR HAVING THE BILA
PUT A NUMBER ON OUR CONTRIBUTION TO THE CITY AND SO
WITH THAT I'M GLAD WE ALSO HAVE NOT ONE BUT TWO LATINO WOMEN ON
THIS BOARD TO CELEBRATE THIS MONTH AND I THINK IT'S VERY
COOL WE GET TO CELEBRATE BOTH OF OUR THE COUNTRY'S
INDEPENDENCE DAY IS ON THE SAME DAY.
>> SO I AM I'M VERY PROUD TO BE MEXICAN-AMERICAN, BE THE FIRST
LATINA WOMAN TO REPRESENT DISTRICT NINE, MY GRANDPARENTS
ON MY MOTHER'S SIDE WERE FROM MONTERREY, MEXICO.
THEY CAME TO THE US FOR A BETTER LIFE LIKE MANY FAMILIES,
MY GRANDMOTHER WHEN SHE WASN'T WORKING TO RAISE FOUR KIDS SHE
WOULD PACK SEE'S CANDY IN FACTORY AND OTHER FACTORY
JOBS AND TAKE CARE OF FOLKS IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD AS WELL AS
HER OWN FAMILY. >> AND MY GRANDPA STARTED OUT
AS A FARM WORKER PICKING ORANGES IN THE ORANGE GROVES OF
SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA AND LATER WOULD TAILOR SUITS FOR A
LIVING. AND THOUGH I NEVER GOT THE
CHANCE TO GROW UP WITH THEM, MY GRANDPARENTS VALUES OF HARD
WORK AND COMMUNITY SERVICE WAS INSTILLED IN ME FROM A YOUNG
AGE THROUGH MY MOM. I'M THE PROUD DAUGHTER OF A
SINGLE MOM UH A LOUD LATINA WOMAN AND IT IS ALL OF THEIR
LEGACY THAT I SEEK TO HONOR IN MY ROLE HERE AT THE BOARD OF
SUPERVISORS AND IN FIGHTING FOR THE MOST VULNERABLE
AND ESPECIALLY WORKING CLASS LATINOS.
SAN FRANCISCO HAS LONG BEEN A HOME AND A BEACON FOR OUR
LATINO COMMUNITY WHERE FAMILIES ,FAMILIES, BUSINESSES AND OUR
CULTURE THRIVES. THE LATINO COMMUNITY PLAYS AN
IMPORTANT ROLE IN OUR ECONOMY AS ESSENTIAL WORKERS ALSO AS
OWNERS, ENTREPRENEURS, INNOVATORS AND OF COURSE
CARETAKERS FOR OUR FOR MANY FOLKS IN SAN FRANCISCO FROM THE
STREET VENDORS ALONG MISSION AND 20 FOURTH 16TH TO THE
VIBRANT MURALS OF BALMY ALLEY TO THE MISSION CULTURAL CENTER
FOR LATINO ARTS THAT IS HOME TO THOUSANDS OF LATINOS PRACTICING
OUR ARTS AND OUR MUSIC DANCE TO THE GENERATIONS OF FAMILIES WHO
HAVE BUILT THIS CITY ALONGSIDE NEWCOMERS ARRIVING WITH A
SHARED SENSE OF HOPE. THIS MONTH IS A TIME TO
CELEBRATE THESE CONTRIBUTIONS OUR ACHIEVEMENTS PERSEVERANCE
AND CREATIVITY AND TO HONOR THE LEADERS, ARTISTS AND ACTIVISTS
WHOSE WORK KEEPS OUR NEIGHBORHOODS VIBRANT FROM
ORGANIZED ON THE GROUND WITH THE LATINO TASK FORCE MISSION
NEIGHBORHOOD CENTERS MISSION ACTION TO THOSE ADVOCATING FOR
HOUSING IMMIGRANTS RIGHTS, CLIMATE JUSTICE AND DEFENDING
OUR DEMOCRACY ALL AT THE SAME TIME.
IT'S ALSO A MOMENT TO REMEMBER OUR STRUGGLES AND RECOMMIT
OURSELVES TO THE FIGHT AHEAD AS OUR HERITAGE HAS ALWAYS BEEN
ONE OF TURNING PAIN INTO POWER AND EXCLUSION INTO BELONGING.
SAN FRANCISCO IS STRONGER BECAUSE OF OUR DIVERSITY AND AS
A REPRESENTATIVE ON THIS BOARD I'M COMMITTED TO ENSURING WITH
ALL MY COLLEAGUES THAT OUR CITY CONTINUES TO BE A PLACE WHERE
EVERYONE BELONGS A TRUE SANCTUARY CITY FOR ALL.
>> THANK YOU. THANK YOU SUPERVISORS MELGAR
AND FIELDER AND I THINK WE CAN TAKE THIS ITEM SAME HOUSE SAME
CALL WITHOUT OBJECTION THE RESOLUTION IS ADOPTED AND MADAM
CLERK DO WE HAVE ANY IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS?
WE HAVE NO IMPERATIVE AGENDA ITEMS TODAY.
MR. PRESIDENT, COULD YOU READ THE IN MEMORIAM?
>> YES. TODAY'S MEETING WILL BE
ADJOURNED IN MEMORY OF THE FOLLOWING BELOVED INDIVIDUALS
ON BEHALF OF PRESIDENT MENDELSOHN FOR THE LATE MR.
RAVEN SORREL ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR WALTON FOR THE LATE
MS. JACQUELINE JACKIE COHEN AND ON BEHALF OF SUPERVISOR
AND ENGARDIO FOR THE LATE MR. QUIET QUEEN WHEN AND I THINK
THAT BRINGS US TO THE END OF OUR AGENDA, MADAM CLERK IS
THERE ANY FURTHER BUSINESS BEFORE US TODAY THAT CONCLUDES
OUR BUSINESS FOR TODAY. >> THANK YOU, MADAM CLERK.
AS THERE'S NO FURTHER BUSINESS WE ARE ADJOURNED